A Guide to the Papers of the National Association of Pediatric Nurse Practitioners, 1972-1992
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- SERIES 1: Administrative Office Documents
  - Subseries: - Correspondence and Related Documents
    - Special Projects January - September 1992 (Box-folder 023-005)
      Re: NAPNAP Participation in Head Injury Prevention, Kids Count Campaign, March of Dimes Walkathon, NCAL Hepatitis B Action Group, Poison Prevention Week
    - Task Force on AIDS/ HIV January - December 1992 (Box-folder 023-006)
      Re: CDC programs, initiatives on AIDS, grant funds for AIDS study, ANA position on sex education and AIDS, AIDS fact sheets, legislation related to AIDS, NORA (National Organizations Responding to AIDS) meetings and activities, World Aids Day at NIH
    - Access to Care Task Force (Health Care Reform) January - May 1992 (Box-folder 023-007)
      Re: Development of NAPNAP position on access to care, and NAPNAP reaction to ANA access statement
    - Access to Care Task Force (Health Care Reform) June - December 1992 (Box-folder 023-008)
      Re: Development of NAPNAP policy statement on access to care, NAPNAP response to ANA position, NAPNAP grants for child immunization and proposed grants for other access projects
    - Task Force on Breastfeeding February - December 1992 (Box-folder 023-009)
      Re: NAPNAP participation in USDA Breastfeeding Promotion Consortium, legislation related to breastfeeding
    - Immunizations Standards Task Force March - December 1992 (Box-folder 023-010)
      Re: NAPNAP approval of standards for Immunization Practice, Immunization Education Action Committee, National Vaccine Advisory Committee
    - Research Agenda Task Force July - October 1992 (Box-folder 024-001)
      Re: Developing NAPNAP policy on research, including research support, grants, finances, etc.
    - Associations: AAP/ NAPNAP February - October 1992 (Box-folder 024-002)
      Re: Cooperative ventures, including school health, community, health initiatives, annual NAPNAP/ AAP meeting
    - Associations: ANA/ NAPNAP March - November 1992 (Box-folder 024-003)
      Re: American Nurses Credentialing Center, ANA and NAPNAP positions on health care reform, standards for pediatric immunization practice, ANA hearings on advanced practice credentialing, opposition to Council of Graduate Medical Education involvement in nursing issues
    - Associations: NAACOG, NANP/ NAPNAP April - December 1992 (Box-folder 024-004)
      Re: NAACOG becoming an independent association from AGOG, NANP directory, ANA policy on credentialing of NPs through the ANCC, position on healthcare reform, report on NANP meeting; recommendation that NAPNAP remain a member of NANP
    - Associations: NANDA/ NAPNAP February - September 1992 (Box-folder 024-005)
      Re: NAPNAP participation in North American Nursing Diagnosis Association and development of position on use of nursing diagnoses by NPs
    - Associations: NASN, NCBPNP/ NAPNAP March - August 1992 (Box-folder 024-006)
      Re: ANA involvement in setting standards for school nursing practice, NAPNAP participation in NCBPNP, NCB statement on credentialing
    - Associations: NFSNO/ NAPNAP January - October 1992 (Box-folder 024-007)
      Re: NAPNAP participation in National Federation of Specialty Nursing Organizations, NFSNO response to National Council of State Boards of Nursing proposal on master's level education and mandatory licensure, other NFSNO business
    - Associations: NOLF/ NAPNAP January - November 1992 (Box-folder 024-008)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: AMA position on health policy issues and position on licensure of advanced practice nursing
    - Associations: NCSBN/ NAPNAP July - October 1992 (Box-folder 024-009)
      Re: Licensure of advanced practice proposal by National Council of State Boards of Nursing, and NAPNAP opposition
    - NAPNAP Foundation: Grants January - December 1992 (Box-folder 024-010)
      Re: Grant applications approved; progress reports
    - NAPNAP Foundation: Business Documents January - November 1992 (Box-folder 024-011)
      Re: Grant procedures, job descriptions, donations, bylaws, finances, Procter & Gamble grants
    - Capitol Associates: AHCPR January - December 1992 (Box-folder 024-012)
      Re: Agency for Health Care Policy and Research, NAPNAP participation in AHCPR task force, AHCPR meetings and activities, calls for nominations to councils & committees, development of clinical standards guidelines
    - Capitol Associates: Boy Scouts, Brady Bill July - November 1992 (Box-folder 025-001)
      Re: Boy Scouts of America approval of physical examinations by NPs, NAPNAP support of Brady Bill
    - Capitol Associates: Child Abuse, Child Health Day, Children First Coalition January - December 1992 (Box-folder 025-002)
      Re: NAPNAP nomination to Child Abuse Board and NAPNAP participation in Child Health Day, the Children First Coalition, and the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development Coalition
    - Capitol Associates: Miscellaneous Children's Issues January - December 1992 (Box-folder 025-003)
      Re: Alliance for Child Survival, Child Health Month, Child Safety issues (consumer products), grants for low-income children, Healthy Children, Healthy Minds conference, Youth Award, child abuse prevention, Kids Count Data Book, Abandoned Infants Assistance Act, children and guns, Comprehensive Youth Act
    - Capitol Associates: CLIA and COGME February - December 1992 (Box-folder 025-004)
      Re: Council on Graduate Medical Education consideration of health manpower issues, Nurse's objections to classification of lab tests as complex by Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendment
    - Capitol Associates: Drug Enforcement Administration January - December 1992 (Box-folder 025-005)
      Re: Assignment of DEA numbers to NPs, NAPNAP opposition to new DEA rules, changes in prescriptive authority for controlled substances, application fees, pediatric drugs
    - Capitol Associates: Family and Medical Leave March - December 1992 (Box-folder 025-006)
      Re: NAPNAP support of Family and Medical Leave legislation, Bush veto
    - Capitol Associates: Gag Rule (Abortion) March - October 1992 (Box-folder 025-007)
      Re: NAPNAP opposition to Gag Rule, legislative attempts to end Gag Rule
    - Capitol Associates: Health Care Reform February - August 1992 (Box-folder 025-008)
      Re: Miscellaneous health care reform legislation (See also folders on NAPNAP "Access to Care" task force)
    - Capitol Associates: Highway Safety Issues January - November 1992 (Box-folder 025-009)
      Re: Legislation, reports on child restraints, bicycle helmets, license restriction, school bus safety, includes NAPNAP comments on highway safety issues to NHTSC
    - Capitol Associates: Infant Mortality February - December 1992 (Box-folder 025-010)
      Re: Infant Mortality Advisory Council activities, NAPNAP nomination of Bulgrin to Council
    - Capitol Associates: Lead Poisoning January - December 1992 (Box-folder 025-011)
      Re: Legislative efforts to end lead poisoning, Alliance to End Childhood Lead Poisoning, Lead Poisoning Prevention Coalition, NAPNAP solicitation of members to serve on lead poisoning task force
    - Capitol Associates: Malpractice Liability January - December 1992 (Box-folder 025-012)
      Re: National Liability Reform Coalition and NAPNAP support of statement on medical liability, liability legislation, National Practitioner Data Bank
    - Capitol Associates: Medicare/ Medicaid, National Health Service Corps, National Health and Education Consortium January - December 1992 (Box-folder 026-001)
      Re: Medicare/ Medicaid issues affecting NPs, National Health Service Corps funding and primary care, National Health Education Consortium activities
    - Capitol Associates: National Institutes of Health January - October 1992 (Box-folder 026-002)
      Re: NIH Strategic Plan, NIH and NCNR funding and budgets
    - Capitol Associates: Nursing Education January - December 1992 (Box-folder 026-003)
      Re: Nurse Education Act Reauthorization, NAPNAP testimony on funding of nurse education, grants and loans, PNP educational funding, Advisory Council on Nurses Education of Health Resources and Services Administration
    - Capitol Associates: Nursing Research January - December 1992 (Box-folder 026-004)
      Re: funding opportunities, National Advisory Council for Nursing Research meeting and report
    - Capitol Associates: Maternal Child Programs, Nursing Shortage, Nutrition, OSHA September 1991 - October 1992 (Box-folder 026-005)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: maternal child health programs, nursing shortage report, nutrition labeling, WIC, Prescription Drug Accountability Act, OSHA legislation
    - Capitol Associates: Miscellaneous Nursing Issues April - October 1992 (Box-folder 026-006)
      Re: Capitol Hill Nurses Caucus reports, National Nursing Week, Virginia APGAR Stamp, Sigma Theta Tau television program for nurses, Division of Nursing activities, CPT coding, letters to NPs on various topics
    - Capitol Associates: Pediatric AIDS Coalition March - November 1992 (Box-folder 026-007)
      Re: Coalition's legislative agenda, meetings, publicity and lobbying activities
    - Capitol Associates: Physician Payment Review Commission February - November 1992 (Box-folder 026-008)
      Re: Reimbursement of NPs, promotion of health professionals in underserved areas, ANA comments PPRC
    - Capitol Associates: Miscellaneous Political and Legislative March - December 1992 (Box-folder 026-009)
      Re: Congressional elections, committee assignments, NAPNAP nominations to commissions and committees, miscellaneous legislation, Appropriations affecting funding for nursing education, research, etc., includes NAPNAP testimony on appropriations
    - Capitol Associates: Rural Health, School-based Clinics, Tuberculosis February - December 1992 (Box-folder 027-001)
      Re: Rural health issues, policies, legislation, school-based clinics, insurance appropriations for TB, TB research and policy
    - Capitol Associates: Third Party Reimbursement January - May 1992 (Box-folder 027-002)
      Re: Legislation affecting NP direct reimbursement
    - Capitol Associates: Third Party Reimbursement June - December 1992 (Box-folder 027-003)
- SERIES 2: Publications and Manuals
  - Subseries: Publications and manuals
    - The Pediatric Nurse Practitioner September 1973 - December 1979 (Box-folder 028-001)
      Re: NAPNAP newsletter
    - The Pediatric Nurse Practitioner January 1980 - December 1984 (Box-folder 028-002)
    - The Pediatric Nurse Practitioner January 1985 - December 1989 (Box-folder 028-003)
    - The Pediatric Nurse Practitioner March 1990 - October 1996 (Box-folder 028-004)
    - NAPNAP Position Statements 1977 - 1994 (Box-folder 028-005)
      Re: Position statements, philosophical statements, white papers about: definition of PNP/ A, entry into practice (1980, 1992), NAPNAP goals and objectives, 1984 legislative platform, infant formula advertising, philosophical statements on children, health and immunization, HIV testing of health care workers, continuing education, third party reimbursement, child abuse/ neglect, corporal punishment, certification for advanced practice (1986, 1992), health care reform for children, PNP educational preparation and role, breastfeeding, child care, and school-based clinics
    - Fact Sheets on NAPNAP, PNPs, 1989 - 1990 (Box-folder 028-006)
      Re: fact sheets on PNPs, background information on NAPNAP
    - Press Releases 1990 - 1991 (Box-folder 028-007)
      Re: Mullins becomes NAPNAP president, call for papers, support for Congressman Matsui
    - Legislative update 1993 (Box-folder 028-008)
      Re: legislative issues affecting NPs
    - NAPNAP informational brochures 1975 - 1990, and n.d. (Box-folder 028-009)
      Re: brochures on NAPNAP, on the pediatric nurse practitioner, on scope of practice, on standards of practice
    - NAPNAP informational brochures 1989, and n.d. (Box-folder 028-010)
      Re: Baby's First Cold, Parents Guide to Choosing Quality Child Care, Child Care Opera-tor's Guidelines, Starting Solids, Mommy/ Daddy - What's AIDS?, Medicine Cabinet Essentials, Why Should a Practicing Pediatric Nurse subscribe to Pediatric Nursing?, Risk Management for Pediatric Nurse Practitioners
    - Continuing Education Seminars 1973 - October 1978 (Box-folder 028-011)
      Re: Programs and registration forms/ flyers for CEU programs by NAPNAP
    - "Nurse Practitioners: Review of the Literature: 1965 - 1979" 1965 - 1982 (Box-folder 028-012)
    - NAPNAP, AAP conference promotional items 1988 - 1991 (Box-folder 028-013)
      Re: Cartoons by Bill Keane with "Family Circus" characters
    - NurSoy Advertisements 1988 - 1989, and n.d. (Box-folder 028-014)
      Re: Original ads by Bill Keane featuring "Family Circus" characters
    - Nursery Grand Rounds Educational Service 1982 (Box-folder 028-015)
      Re: NAPNAP & Wyeth Laboratories produced cassette tape and flyers
    - NAPNAP Conference Programs 1980 - 1985 (Box-folder 029-001)
      Re: Flyers, programs from annual conferences
    - NAPNAP Conference Programs 1986 - 1987 (Box-folder 029-002)
      Re: Programs from annual conferences
    - NAPNAP Conference Programs 1989 - 1990 (Box-folder 029-003)
    - NAPNAP Conference Programs 1991 - 1992 (Box-folder 029-004)
    - NAPNAP Conference Programs 1993 - 1994 (Box-folder 029-005)
    - NAPNAP Conference Programs 1995 - 1996 (Box-folder 029-006)
    - NAPNAP Conference Programs 1998 (Box-folder 029-007)
- SERIES 3: Chapters documents
  - Subseries: Chapters documents
    - NAPNAP Chapter's Bulletin January 1986 - December 1987 (Box-folder 030-001)
      Re: Newsletter sent to NAPNAP chapters
    - NAPNAP Chapter's Bulletin January 1988 - December 1989 (Box-folder 030-002)
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Charter 1978 - 1982 (Box-folder 030-003)
      Re: Original charter documents for various chapters
    - Chapter Documents: Chapter Charters 1983 - 1992 (Box-folder 030-004)
      Re: Original charter documents for individual chapters
    - NAPNAP Chapters 1974 - 1978, and n.d. (Box-folder 030-005)
      Re: Formation of chapters, legal status of chapters
    - NAPNAP Chapters 1980, 1984 (Box-folder 030-006)
      Re: Chapter approval, operations and procedures
    - NAPNAP Chapters 1985, 1986, 1987, 1988 (Box-folder 030-007)
      Re: Chapter President's meetings minutes, invitation to NAPNAP conference, call for chapter reporters, chapter bulletin planned stories, suggestions for stories, Wyeth large and small chapter awards, Greater Boston Chapter dissolution, Utah Chapter dissolution, South Carolina Chapter dissolution
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapters Committee March - December 1989 (Box-folder 030-008)
      Re: Requirement that chapter officers belong to national NAPNAP organization, instructions for annual reports, chapter membership chairs, miscellaneous business, chapter presidents input plans, chapter statistics, newsletter ideas
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Reports 1989 (Box-folder 030-009)
      Re: Annual reports of state chapters: Arkansas, California (Los Angeles, Orange County, Riverside, San Diego, San Joaquin), Colorado, Florida, Illinois, Indiana, Iowa
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Reports 1989 (Box-folder 030-010)
      Re: Annual reports of state chapters: Maryland, Massachusetts, Michigan, Military, Min-nesota, Missouri, New Jersey, New York
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Reports 1989 (Box-folder 030-011)
      Re: Annual reports of state chapters: North Carolina, Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon, Pennsylvania, Texas, Houston TX, Washington, Wisconsin
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapters Coordinator January - December 1990 (Box-folder 030-012)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: chapter booths at conference, NAPNAP position on marketing infant formula, chapter president's meeting reports and plans, chapter contacts, use of NAPNAP logo, Executive Board meeting report, Wyeth Chapter Awards, Johnson & Johnson Travel Fellowships, Nurse-in-Washington Internship
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Legislative Chair July - November 1990 (Box-folder 030-013)
      Re: Monthly legislative updates to chapters from NAPNAP legislative chairperson, requests for action to influence legislation
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Reports 1990 (Box-folder 031-001)
      Re: Annual reports of state chapters: Arkansas, California (Los Angeles, Orange County, Riverside, San Diego, San Joaquin), Colorado, Connecticut
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Reports 1990 (Box-folder 031-002)
      Re: Annual reports of state chapters: Florida, Georgia, Illinois, Indiana, Iowa Maryland, (western) Massachusetts, Michigan, Military, Minnesota, Missouri (Kansas City, St. Louis)
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Reports 1990 (Box-folder 031-003)
      Re: Annual reports of state chapters: New Jersey, New York (Greater NY and Western NY), North Carolina, Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon, Pennsylvania (Delaware Valley), Texas, Houston TX, Washington, Wisconsin
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Coordinator January - December 1991 (Box-folder 031-004)
      Re: Johnson & Johnson Travel Fellowship, chapter awards, chapter president's meeting, membership in NAPNAP issues, annual report procedures, NFNSO Nurse-in-Washington Internship, legislative issues, policy/ public relations emphases
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Legislative Chair January - December 1991 (Box-folder 031-005)
      Re: Monthly legislative updates to individual chapters, requests for action to influence legislation, committee membership correspondence, and NAPNAP legislative priorities
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Reports 1991 (Box-folder 031-006)
      Re: Annual reports of state chapters: Arkansas, California (Los Angeles, Orange County, Northern, Riverside, San Diego, San Joaquin), Colorado, Connecticut, Florida, Georgia, Illinois (Chicago)
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Reports 1991 (Box-folder 031-007)
      Re: Annual reports of state chapters: Indiana, Iowa, Maryland, Massachusetts (Eastern, Western), Michigan, Military, Minnesota, Missouri (Kansas City, St. Louis), New Jersey
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Reports 1991 (Box-folder 032-001)
      Re: Annual reports of state chapters: New York (Greater NY and Western NY), North Carolina, Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon, Pennsylvania (Delaware Valley), Texas (Greater TX and Houston), Washington, Wisconsin
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Coordinator January - December 1992 (Box-folder 032-002)
      Re: Wyeth chapter awards, Johnson & Johnson travel grants, problems with annual reports, chapter president's meeting, chapter booths at conference Nurse-in-Washington In-ternship, new chapters, problems with chapter members not being NAPNAP members, physical exams by PNPs in Wisconsin, chapter by-laws
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Legislative Chair January - April 1992 (Box-folder 032-003)
      Re: Monthly legislative updates to chapters, correspondence with individual chapters about regional issues
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Reports 1992 (Box-folder 032-004)
      Re: Annual reports of state chapters: Arkansas, California (Los Angeles, Orange County, Northern, Riverside, San Diego, San Joaquin), Colorado, Connecticut, Florida, Georgia, Illinois (Chicago), Indiana
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Reports 1992 (Box-folder 032-005)
      Re: Annual reports of state chapters: Iowa, Maryland, Massachusetts (Eastern & Western), Michigan, Military, Minnesota, Missouri (Kansas City & St. Louis), New Jersey
    - NAPNAP Chapters: Chapter Reports 1992 (Box-folder 032-006)
      Re: Annual reports of state chapters: New York (Greater NY and Western NY), North Carolina, Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon, Pennsylvania (Delaware Valley), Texas (Greater TX and Houston), Virginia, Washington, Wisconsin
- SERIES 4: Photographs
  - Subseries: Photographs
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Meetings 1973, 1974 (Box-folder 033-001)
      Re: Photos from first annual business meeting, San Francisco, California 1974, from various other meetings and seminars
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Meetings 1975 (Box-folder 033-002)
      Re: Photos from business meeting, board meeting, conference
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Meetings 1977 (Box-folder 033-003)
      Re: Photos from conference, reception
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Conferences March 1983 (Box-folder 033-004)
      Re: Photos from annual conference, Chicago Illinois
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Conferences 1985, 1986, 1987 (Box-folder 033-005)
      Re: Photos from annual conferences, executive board meeting
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Conferences March 1988 (Box-folder 033-006)
      Re: Photos from annual conference, Boston, MA
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Conferences March 1988 (Box-folder 033-007)
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Conferences March 1988 (Box-folder 033-008)
      Re: Photos from annual conference, executive meeting, Boston, MA
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Conferences 1989, 1990, and 1991 (Box-folder 033-009)
      Re: Photos from annual conferences: 1989 Orlando, FL, 1990 San Francisco, CA, and 1991 Philadelphia, PA
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Conferences March 1994 (Box-folder 033-010)
      Re: Photos from annual conferences, Chicago, IL
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Conferences March 1994 (Box-folder 033-011)
      Re: Photos from annual conference, Chicago, IL
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Archives Reception/ Conferences 1995 (Box-folder 033-012)
      Re: Photos from NAPNAP archives reception, University of Virginia, May 1995 and annual conference, March 1995
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Conferences March 1996 (Box-folder 033-013)
      Re: Photos from annual conference, San Diego, CA
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Conferences March 1996 (Box-folder 033-014)
    - NAPNAP Photographs: Miscellaneous 1973, 1995, 1998 and n.d. (Box-folder 033-015)
      Re: Photos of NAPNAP officers and miscellaneous, past presidents
- SERIES 5: Audiotapes
  - Subseries: Audiotapes
    - Audiotapes 1982-1986 (Box-folder 034)
      Wyeth/NAPNAP Nursery Grand Rounds tapes
    - Audiotapes 1981-1983 (Box-folder 035)
      NAPNAP Conference Tapes
    - Audiotapes 1984-1986 (Box-folder 036)
    - Audiotapes 1987 - 1989 (Box-folder 037)
    - Audiotapes 1990 - 1991 (Box-folder 038)
    - Audiotapes 1992 - 1993 (Box-folder 039)
- SERIES 6: Videotapes
  - Subseries: Videotapes
    - Videotapes
      Re: Separated from main collection and housed in Center for Nursing Historical Inquiry